Mohammad R. Tayyebi

(+98) 912 098-2276 | smile@tyyi.net | linkedin.com/in/mohammadrezatayyebi | github.com/tayyebi

Profile

Award winning software developer and IT project manager, with Master of Business Administration (MBA) and Bachelor of Computer Engineering (CE) background. Experienced in architecture and development of clean, lite, and stable back-end APIs and high-frequency database queries. Skilled in installation, maintenance, and rescue of Microsoft Windows and Linux servers and some cloud technologies. Able to design and ensure the quality and time limitations of IT projects a deep understanding of business requirements such as finance, marketing, and human capitals. Comfortable with diverse teams in case of gender, professional background, nationality, position, approach, and work/life style.

EDUCATION

Khaje Nasir Toosi University of Technology

Tehran, IR

Hamedan, IR

MBA, Minor in Marketing Management

Oct. 2021 - July 2023

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering, Minor in Information Technology

Mar. 2014 - July 2020

EXPERIENCE

IT Project Manager

Bu-Ali Sina University

June 2022 – Dec. 2022

Tokan Tav Tejarat

Full-time on-site — Hamedan, IR

- Architecture and establishing code-base for an online marketplace mostly using PHP.
- Project management, monitoring cost, project timing, team motivation, and quality tests.
- Installation, containerization, and maintenance of required infrastructure for production and development containing GIT, CDN, SMTP, KMS, workflow, FTP, monitoring, and database servers

IT Consultant and Web Developer

June 2022 – Present

Universal Versatile Society

Part-time Remote — Maharashtra, IN

- Team organization and training, editorial of project proposals, co-leadership of the tech team, and documentation standardization.
- Back-end implementation on Python stack.
- Front-end implementation on PHP

PHP & ASP.NET Core C# Developer

Jan 2021 – May 2021

MrBilit Group

Full-time Remote — Isfahan, IR

- Code refactor and re-write from old PHP stack to company's modern and integrated domain driven designed ASP.NET Core C# stack.
- Development of APIs and bots to keep databses sync and serve up-to-date data to hundred of thousands of human and bot users.

Freelancer & Independent Contractor

July 2012 – Present

Hybrid

Teacher

- Private programming tutor and coach in some companies.
- Full-stack enterpriese software developer workshop teacher at Scientific Society of Computer Science and Engineering of Bu-Ali Sina University.
- Advanced MVC Design Pattern crash course teacher at Scientific Society of Computer Science and Engineering of Bu-Ali Sina University.
- Teaching ASP.NET Web Forms, WCF, WPF, Xamarin, Windows Forms Applications and SQL Server at Khaje Nasir Institute of Technical and Vocational Training.
- Teaching ActionScript programming and game design with Adobe Flash CS5 at Madani High School.

Full-stack Developer

- IoT and socket programming.
- Business analysis and database design.
- Servers configuration and tuning.
- Web design and development.

WorldSkills | Champion, National Gold Medalist

2017 • Abu-Dhabi, AE

- IT Software Solutions for Business.
- 4 days of web, desktop and mobile programming, business analysis, and problem solving in competition with tens of talented youth from different countries.

Khwarizmi Youth Award | National Ranked 3^{rd}

2015 • Tehran, IR

- Computer Science
- Development of a centralized authentication and authorization system
- Being among 45 selected students out of 25339 and awarded in the most creditable scientific festival of Iran, known as Khwarizmi, even before attending university.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C#, PHP

Developer Tools: Git, Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio

Database Systems: SQL Server, MySQL

Server Administration: Windows Sevrer, Debian/Ubuntu Linux, Docker